On his way to finding a legend...he will become one.
Legend of the Guardians: The Owls of Ga'Hoole is a animation,
adventure, family film directed by Zack Snyder.
When a young owl is abducted by an evil Owl army, he must escape with new-found
friends and seek the legendary Guardians to stop the menace.
Soren (voice), played by Jim Sturgess.
Kludd (voice), played by Ryan Kwanten.
Noctus / Grimble (voice), played by Hugo Weaving.
Nyra (voice), played by Helen Mirren.
Ezylryb (voice), played by Geoffrey Rush.
Gylfie (voice), played by Emily Barclay.
Legend of the Guardians: The Owls of Ga'Hoole is a 2010 animated
fantasy adventure film directed by Zack Snyder.
Based on the Guardians of Ga'Hoole book series by Kathryn Lasky, the film was written by John Orloff and Emil Stern and features the voices of Helen Mirren, Geoffrey Rush,
Jim Sturgess, Hugo Weaving, Emily Barclay, Abbie Cornish, Ryan Kwanten, Anthony LaPaglia, Miriam Margolyes, Sam Neill, Richard Roxburgh, and David Wenham.
An international co-production between the United States and Australia, the film was produced by Village
Roadshow Pictures and Animal Logic, following their success with the 2006 film Happy Feet.
In the film, Soren (Sturgess), a barn owl, is kidnapped and taken to St.
Aegolius Academy for Orphaned Owls led by Metal Beak (Joel Edgerton) and Nyra
(Mirren), where owlets are brainwashed into becoming soldiers.
He befriends a fellow owl named Gylfie (Barclay), and they later escape the facility to find the
Island of Ga'Hoole with new-found friends and together fight against the evil army.
Legend of the Guardians was theatrically released in RealD 3D and IMAX 3D in North America on
September 24, 2010, and in Australia on September 30, 2010, by Warner Bros.
Pictures; it was accompanied by a new 3D Looney
Tunes cartoon entitled Fur of Flying.
The film grossed over $140 million worldwide against a budget of $80 million.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised its dark tone, animation, and voice
performances, but criticized its changes made to the source material.
The film explores themes of friendship, villain, heroism,
brother against brother, clash of clans.